[
    {
        "question": "1. (401) How many conductors must a clamp-on ammeter encircle to obtain an accurate current reading? ",
        "options": [
            "a. One.",
            "b. Two.",
            "c. Three.",
            "d. Four."
        ],
        "correct": "a. One."
    },
    {
        "question": "2. (402) Which measurement determines the length of a screwdriver? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Overall length.",
            "b. Length of the tip.",
            "c. Length of the shank.",
            "d. Length of the blade."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Length of the shank."
    },
    {
        "question": "3. (402) When using an adjustable wrench, why do you not apply a pulling force to the adjustable jaw?",
        "options": [
            "a. The wrench is likely to slip.",
            "b. You could break your wrist.",
            "c. The wrench is likely to bend.",
            "d. You could break your fingers."
        ],
        "correct": "a. The wrench is likely to slip."
    },
    {
        "question": "4. (403) What tool should you use to cut openings when installing devices in finished walls? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Crosscut saw.",
            "b. Compass saw.",
            "c. Ripsaw.",
            "d. Jab saw."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Jab saw."
    },
    {
        "question": "5. (403) How is a hacksaw blade installed?",
        "options": [
            "a. Users preference.",
            "b. Teeth facing away from handle.",
            "c. Teeth facing towards the handle.",
            "d. Depends on material that is being cut."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Teeth facing away from handle."
    },
    {
        "question": "6. (404) What conduit bender is normally used for ½\" and ¾\" EMT?",
        "options": [
            "a. Hickey bender.",
            "b. Electric bender.",
            "c. One-shot bender.",
            "d. Hydraulic bender."
        ],
        "correct": "c. One-shot bender."
    },
    {
        "question": "7. (405) How do you know when a bit is properly tightened in a cordless drill? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Use a wrench to tighten the chuck.",
            "b. You tighten it ½ turn past snug.",
            "c. You will hear a clicking sound.",
            "d. Until it doesn't move."
        ],
        "correct": "c. You will hear a clicking sound."
    },
    {
        "question": "8. (406) What is the largest American standard wire gauge (AWG) size electrical wire? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 1/0.",
            "b. 2/0.",
            "c. 3/0.",
            "d. 4/0."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 4/0."
    },
    {
        "question": "9. (406) The kcmil size range for conductors is ",
        "options": [
            "a. 100 to 1,000.",
            "b. 200 to 2,000.",
            "c. 250 to 2,000.",
            "d. 250 to 2,500."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 250 to 2,000."
    },
    {
        "question": "10. (407) Pre-punched disks in a box that can be removed easily to permit conduit or cable connectors to be installed are called ",
        "options": [
            "a. blanks.",
            "b. pryouts.",
            "c. knockouts.",
            "d. connector disks."
        ],
        "correct": "c. knockouts."
    },
    {
        "question": "11. (408) What is the purpose of a raised box cover? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Provides space for three additional devices.",
            "b. Allows for installation of a thicker wall surface after the box is mounted.",
            "c. Allows the box to be mounted five eighths of an inch behind the wall surface. d. Provides added interior space as well as a cover for the box.",
            "d. Provides added interior space as well as a cover for the box."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Provides added interior space as well as a cover for the box."
    },
    {
        "question": "12. (409) When you are connecting rigid conduit to boxes, what is/are required for circuits above 250 volts?  ",
        "options": [
            "a. One locknut and a bushing.",
            "b. Two locknuts and a bushing.",
            "c. Two bushings and a locknut.",
            "d. Two bushings and two locknuts."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Two locknuts and a bushing."
    },
    {
        "question": "13. (409) Which condition below is not allowed?  ",
        "options": [
            "a. Using flexible metal tubing in lengths less than 6 feet.",
            "b. Using flexible metal tubing in lengths greater than 6 feet.",
            "c. Using rigid metal conduit in lengths greater than 6 feet.",
            "d. Using liquid-tight flexible metal conduit in lengths greater than 6 feet."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Using flexible metal tubing in lengths greater than 6 feet."
    },
    {
        "question": "14. (410) Which ratings are always found on switches? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Volts and watts.",
            "b. Amperes and volts.",
            "c. Amperes and watts.",
            "d. Resistance and hertz."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Amperes and volts."
    },
    {
        "question": "15. (411) What does the label TR signify on duplex receptacles? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Test regularly.",
            "b. Tamper resistant.",
            "c. Test resistor.",
            "d. Training regulation."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Tamper resistant."
    },
    {
        "question": "16. (412) Which part of a set of blueprints indicates the route of the service entrance? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Exterior elevations.",
            "b. Interior elevations.",
            "c. Detail drawings.",
            "d. Plot plan."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Plot plan."
    },
    {
        "question": "17. (413) The simplest form of electrical diagrams is the ",
        "options": [
            "a. block diagram.",
            "b. wiring diagram.",
            "c. schematic diagram.",
            "d. connection diagram."
        ],
        "correct": "a. block diagram."
    },
    {
        "question": "18. (414) The normal color code for wiring a device is ",
        "options": [
            "a. white to gold terminal, black to silver.",
            "b. black to gold terminal, red to silver.",
            "c. black to gold terminal, white to silver.",
            "d. red to gold terminal, black to silver."
        ],
        "correct": "c. black to gold terminal, white to silver."
    },
    {
        "question": "19. (415) What is the general lighting load of an office building with 1,600 square feet of living area?",
        "options": [
            "a. 533 watts.",
            "b. 560 watts.",
            "c. 5,333 watts.",
            "d. 5,600 watts."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 5,600 watts."
    },
    {
        "question": "20. (416) What is the total wattage of 9 ballasts rated at 1.5 amps each and fed by 277 volts? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 1,350.",
            "b. 3,739.",
            "c. 4,155.",
            "d. 42,930."
        ],
        "correct": "b. 3,739."
    },
    {
        "question": "21. (416) Heavy-duty lamp-holder outlets are calculated at ",
        "options": [
            "a. 300 volt-ohms.",
            "b. 300 volt-amperes.",
            "c. 600 volt-ohms.",
            "d. 600 volt-amperes."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 600 volt-amperes."
    },
    {
        "question": "22. (416) What is the required wattage for lighting of an industrial commercial (loft) building measuring 60 by 100 feet? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 6,000.",
            "b. 12,000.",
            "c. 18,000.",
            "d. 24,000."
        ],
        "correct": "b. 12,000."
    },
    {
        "question": "23. (417) The code letter on a motor data plate identifies ",
        "options": [
            "a. the manufacturer's name.",
            "b. the voltage required for starting.",
            "c. the current required for starting.",
            "d. the locked-rotor current draw."
        ],
        "correct": "d. the locked-rotor current draw."
    },
    {
        "question": "24. (418) To determine the total calculated load of a sub-panel, you should add all the amperages of the branch circuits plus what percent of the amperage of the largest motor? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 10.",
            "b. 15.",
            "c. 25.",
            "d. 30."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 25."
    },
    {
        "question": "25. (419) How many current carrying conductors can be installed in raceway before the current capacity of the conductors must be de-rated? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Two.",
            "b. Three.",
            "c. Four.",
            "d. Five."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Three."
    },
    {
        "question": "26. (419) All of the following are important when paralleling conductors, except what? ",
        "options": [
            "a. All conductors must be the same color.",
            "b. Phases and neutrals must be separated.",
            "c. Each neutral is run with its corresponding phases.",
            "d. All conductors must be of same material, size and length."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Phases and neutrals must be separated."
    },
    {
        "question": "27. (420) How many conductors are required for a 3-phase-wye service entrance used for power and lighting? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Four ungrounded conductors.",
            "b. Three ungrounded conductors.",
            "c. Three ungrounded and one grounded neutral conductors.",
            "d. Two ungrounded and one grounded neutral conductors."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Three ungrounded and one grounded neutral conductors."
    },
    {
        "question": "28. (421) A transformer that has primary and secondary turns in a ratio of 1 to 10, respectively, is a ",
        "options": [
            "a. step-up transformer.",
            "b. power transformer.",
            "c. step-down transformer.",
            "d. distribution transformer."
        ],
        "correct": "a. step-up transformer."
    },
    {
        "question": "29. (422) Power operated service disconnects are required to be designed so that they can be opened ",
        "options": [
            "a. externally.",
            "b. manually.",
            "c. quickly.",
            "d. slowly."
        ],
        "correct": "b. manually."
    },
    {
        "question": "30. (423) Two ways to keep rain from entering service entrance (SE) cables are to use a weatherhead or ",
        "options": [
            "a. entrance ell.",
            "b. rain cap.",
            "c. gooseneck.",
            "d. junction box."
        ],
        "correct": "c. gooseneck."
    },
    {
        "question": "31. (424) An underground distribution system is referred to as a service ",
        "options": [
            "a. entrance.",
            "b. feeder.",
            "c. lateral.",
            "d. burial."
        ],
        "correct": "c. lateral."
    },
    {
        "question": "32. (424) Underground services installed with cable must be buried to a depth of at least ",
        "options": [
            "a. 18 inches.",
            "b. 24 inches.",
            "c. 30 inches.",
            "d. 36 inches."
        ],
        "correct": "b. 24 inches."
    },
    {
        "question": "33. (425) In a panel with a neutral, what percentage is the smallest of the overcurrent devices that must be rated at 30 amperes or less for it to be classed as a lighting and appliance panel? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 5.",
            "b. 10.",
            "c. 20.",
            "d. 25."
        ],
        "correct": "b. 10."
    },
    {
        "question": "34. (426) When installing a panelboard in a damp location, what number of inches is the minimum distance the cabinet must be placed from the wall? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 1/8.",
            "b. 1/4.",
            "c. 3/8.",
            "d. 1/2."
        ],
        "correct": "b. 1/4."
    },
    {
        "question": "35. (426) The equipment ground bar and neutral bar are bonded together in a panel only when the panelboard also serves as the ",
        "options": [
            "a. distribution feeder.",
            "b. service lateral.",
            "c. load center.",
            "d. service entrance equipment."
        ],
        "correct": "d. service entrance equipment."
    },
    {
        "question": "36. (426) The purpose of balancing the load on a panelboard is to  ",
        "options": [
            "a. reduce voltage drop.",
            "b. increase voltage drop.",
            "c. reduce total current flow. d. increase neutral current flow.",
            "d. increase neutral current flow."
        ],
        "correct": "a. reduce voltage drop."
    },
    {
        "question": "37. (427) Which one of these circuits requires the use of GFCI protection? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 120 V/20 A receptacles in bathrooms.",
            "b. 120 V/20 A receptacles in bedrooms.",
            "c. 240 V/50 A range circuit. d. 240 V/30 A dryer circuit.",
            "d. 240 V/30 A dryer circuit."
        ],
        "correct": "a. 120 V/20 A receptacles in bathrooms."
    },
    {
        "question": "38. (428) The conductors between the final overcurrent devices and the outlets for connecting electrical equipment are called ",
        "options": [
            "a. supply conductors.",
            "b. feeder conductors.",
            "c. distribution conductors.",
            "d. branch circuit conductors."
        ],
        "correct": "d. branch circuit conductors."
    },
    {
        "question": "39. (429) What number is the CPS (Hertz) rating for most electrical equipment found in foreign countries? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 25.",
            "b. 50.",
            "c. 60.",
            "d. 400."
        ],
        "correct": "b. 50."
    },
    {
        "question": "40. (430) What electrical component is the normal use of an octagonal box?",
        "options": [
            "a. Switches.",
            "b. Lighting outlet.",
            "c. Receptacle outlet.",
            "d. Special purpose receptacle."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Lighting outlet."
    },
    {
        "question": "41. (431) What component must be equipped with a metal box used for an old-work installation? ",
        "options": [
            "a. F straps.",
            "b. Support ears.",
            "c. Spring metal clips.",
            "d. Self-tapping screws."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Support ears."
    },
    {
        "question": "42. (432) What metallic cable has a #16 AWG aluminum bonding wire but does not have a green grounding conductor? ",
        "options": [
            "a. .Health care facility cable (HCF)",
            "b. Mineral insulated cable (MI).",
            "c. Metal clad cable (MC).",
            "d. Armored cable (AC)."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Armored cable (AC)."
    },
    {
        "question": "43. (433) How is the minimum bend radius of metal clad cable calculated? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Multiply the radius of the cable by 5.",
            "b. Multiply the cables outside diameter by 5.",
            "c. Multiply the cables outside diameter by 7.",
            "d. Multiply the radius of the cable by 7."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Multiply the cables outside diameter by 7."
    },
    {
        "question": "44. (434) A pigtail splice is finished with ",
        "options": [
            "a. plastic tape.",
            "b. a wire nut.",
            "c. epoxy resin.",
            "d. rubber and friction tape."
        ],
        "correct": "b. a wire nut."
    },
    {
        "question": "45. (435) In addition to the splices required, grounding connections must be made to the boxes used in a circuit to ensure that they are ",
        "options": [
            "a. \"hot.\"",
            "b. \"cold.\"",
            "c. grounded.",
            "d. insulated."
        ],
        "correct": "c. grounded."
    },
    {
        "question": "46. (436) The maximum weight of a fixture that can be supported by an outlet box is",
        "options": [
            "a. 10 pounds.",
            "b. 20 pounds.",
            "c. 40 pounds.",
            "d. 50 pounds."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 50 pounds."
    },
    {
        "question": "47. (437) What is the taper per inch standard conduit-cutting die used on rigid metal conduit? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 1/4 inch.",
            "b. 1/2 inch.",
            "c. 3/4 inch.",
            "d. 1 inch."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 3/4 inch."
    },
    {
        "question": "48. (438) Bends made to conduit while on the job are called ",
        "options": [
            "a. field bends.",
            "b. manual bends.",
            "c. working bends.",
            "d. handmade bends."
        ],
        "correct": "a. field bends."
    },
    {
        "question": "49. (439) When a number of conduit runs are to be installed parallel and adjacent to each other you should install the  ",
        "options": [
            "a. largest conduit first.",
            "b. smallest conduit first.",
            "c. smallest conduit on top. d. conduit all at the same time.",
            "d. conduit all at the same time."
        ],
        "correct": "d. conduit all at the same time."
    },
    {
        "question": "50. (439) Electrical metallic tubing (EMT) and IMC require supports within how many inches and feet of each outlet box, junction box, cabinet, or fitting, and every other foot thereafter. ",
        "options": [
            "a. 36 inches/10 feet.",
            "b. 18 inches/5feet.",
            "c. 12 inches/3 feet.",
            "d. 18 inches/5 feet."
        ],
        "correct": "a. 36 inches/10 feet."
    },
    {
        "question": "51. (440) The number of conductors you can put in conduit is based on the ",
        "options": [
            "a. size of conduit, conductor insulation, and length of run.",
            "b. size of conduit, conductor size, and conductor insulation.",
            "c. size of conductor, length of run, and number of bends.",
            "d. conductor insulation , length of run, and number of bends."
        ],
        "correct": "b. size of conduit, conductor size, and conductor insulation."
    },
    {
        "question": "52. (441) Which of these items is not a part of a direct current (DC) motor? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Stator.",
            "b. Endbells.",
            "c. Armature.",
            "d. Brush assembly."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Stator."
    },
    {
        "question": "53. (442) The direct current (DC) shunt motor connects the field coils and armature in ",
        "options": [
            "a. series.",
            "b. parallel.",
            "c. series-parallel.",
            "d. parallel-series."
        ],
        "correct": "b. parallel."
    },
    {
        "question": "54. (443) The component of a three-phase motor connected to the load is the ",
        "options": [
            "a. armature.",
            "b. endbell.",
            "c. rotor.",
            "d. stator."
        ],
        "correct": "c. rotor."
    },
    {
        "question": "55. (444) The magnetic field of a three-phase motor rotor is caused by a. resistance in the squirrel cage. b. current flow in the rotor. ",
        "options": [
            "a. resistance in the squirrel cage.",
            "b. current flow in the rotor.",
            "c. impedance of the stator.",
            "d. voltage in the end bells."
        ],
        "correct": "b. current flow in the rotor."
    },
    {
        "question": "56. (445) Which of the following features describes three-phase motors best?",
        "options": [
            "a. Either single- or dual-voltage motors.",
            "b. Must be supplied by 220 volts.",
            "c. Always single-voltage motors.",
            "d. Always dual-voltage motors."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Either single- or dual-voltage motors."
    },
    {
        "question": "57. (446) The motor that requires some starting means is the ",
        "options": [
            "a. universal motor.",
            "b. direct current (DC) shunt motor.",
            "c. three-phase alternating current (AC) motor.",
            "d. single-phase AC motor."
        ],
        "correct": "d. single-phase AC motor."
    },
    {
        "question": "58. (447) Which of the following motors has the highest horsepower-to-weight ratio? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Direct current shunt motor.",
            "b. Universal motor.",
            "c. Three-phase dual-voltage motor.",
            "d. Single-phase capacitor start motor."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Universal motor."
    },
    {
        "question": "59. (448) A single-phase motor with external leads numbered T1, T2, T3, T4 is what type? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Single-voltage nonreversible.",
            "b. Single-voltage reversible.",
            "c. Dual-voltage nonreversible.",
            "d. Dual-voltage reversible."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Dual-voltage nonreversible."
    },
    {
        "question": "60. (449) Normally, an across-the-line motor control incorporates some type of ",
        "options": [
            "a. motor over-current protection.",
            "b. lightning protection.",
            "c. motor speed control.",
            "d. frequency control."
        ],
        "correct": "a. motor over-current protection."
    },
    {
        "question": "61. (450) The basic types of overload relays are ",
        "options": [
            "a. thermal and magnetic.",
            "b. single- and three-phase.",
            "c. mechanical and magnetic.",
            "d. undervoltage and overcurrent."
        ],
        "correct": "a. thermal and magnetic."
    },
    {
        "question": "62. (451) The methods used to open the contacts on an across-the-line magnetic controller are ",
        "options": [
            "a. spring tension and gravity.",
            "b. magnetic and thermal.",
            "c. thermal and hydraulic.",
            "d. metallic and magnetic."
        ],
        "correct": "a. spring tension and gravity."
    },
    {
        "question": "63. (451) A temperature-sensitive device to operate a magnetic across-the-line starter automatically is a ",
        "options": [
            "a. thermostat.",
            "b. float switch.",
            "c. pressure switch.",
            "d. photoelectric cell."
        ],
        "correct": "a. thermostat."
    },
    {
        "question": "64. (452) What are the three sections of a variable frequency drive? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Converter, alternating current (AC) Bus, and Inverter.",
            "b. Converter, direct current (DC) Bus, and Inverter.",
            "c. Pulse width modulation (PWM) Converter, DC Bus, and Inverter.",
            "d. Converter, Rectifier, and Inverter."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Converter, direct current (DC) Bus, and Inverter."
    },
    {
        "question": "65. (453) What type of bearing should be used in a vertically-mounted motor?",
        "options": [
            "a. Oillite sleeve.",
            "b. Bronze sleeve.",
            "c. Ball or roller.",
            "d. Phenolic and brass sleeve."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Ball or roller."
    },
    {
        "question": "66. (454) When you clean a motor with compressed air, what is the maximum air pressure to use? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 15 pounds per square inch (psi).",
            "b. 30 psi.",
            "c. 35 psi.",
            "d. 50 psi."
        ],
        "correct": "b. 30 psi."
    },
    {
        "question": "67. (455) If a motor has been operating normally but suddenly stops, you should suspect ",
        "options": [
            "a. improper connections.",
            "b. electrical overload.",
            "c. overvoltage.",
            "d. worn brushes."
        ],
        "correct": "b. electrical overload."
    },
    {
        "question": "68. (455) The end play of a motor should not exceed ",
        "options": [
            "a. 1/8 of an inch.",
            "b. 1/16 of an inch.",
            "c. 1/32 of an inch.",
            "d. 1/64 of an inch."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 1/64 of an inch."
    },
    {
        "question": "69. (456) The conductor common to both the starting and holding circuits is connected to terminal ",
        "options": [
            "a. L1.",
            "b. T1.",
            "c. L2.",
            "d. T2."
        ],
        "correct": "a. L1."
    },
    {
        "question": "70. (457) A motor that operates slowly may have a ",
        "options": [
            "a. deficient voltage supply.",
            "b. ventilation problem.",
            "c. bad conductor.",
            "d. blown fuse."
        ],
        "correct": "a. deficient voltage supply."
    }
]